Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Caricatures and Cartoons 1643, 1756-1943, 1977 PR 10
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Late 19th Century, 1869-1899
  - No title. [Rotund figure stands in foreground having coin for a head inscribed "In Trusts I Trust", his trousers labeled "Surplus Fat". Uncle Sam unloads bag of money into the creature's pocket labeled "Unnecessary Taxation for the Benefit of Monopolists Only $". Civil War veterans begging in background left and "United States of Trusts" Capitol in background right.], 1888 (Folder FF-118, Item 1888-13)
    Pen and ink drawing: Signed Th:Nast. 1888.
  - Polished Off. "Golly - he's licked!!" [African-Americans], 1888 (Folder FF-118, Item 1888-14)
  - Imagerie d'Epinal cartoons, circa 1888 (Folder FF-119, Item 1888-No #)
    Collection of Broadsides for Children, #1,9,21,38,40. "Printed expressly for the Humoristic Publishing Co., Kansas City, Mo." Imagerie d'Epinal--Pellerin, imp-edit.
  - "Viscount Dangan", 1889 (Folder FF-120, Item 1889-1)
    Lithograph, colored: Vincent Brooks, Day & Son, Lith. Signed "Spy". Reproduced in "Vanity Fair," Jan. 12, 1889.
  - "Barnum", 1889 (Folder FF-120, Item 1889-2)
    Lithograph, colored: Vincent Brooks, Day & Son, Lith. Signed "Spy". Reproduced in "Vanity Fair," Nov. 16, 1889.
  - Keep Them - On A Run!! (The Mulberry St. Dive.), 1889 (Folder FF-120, Item 1889-3)
    Pen drawing: Signed Th:Nast. Acquisition(?) date on back: "Rec'd March 30, 1944"
  - No title. [Prosperous looking man stands studying ticker tape while two laborers become stangled by "Wall Street" tape. On the base of ticker tape receiver is the label, "The Quickest Route to go to the Wall." The basket bears the label "Life Wasted," with image of Trinity Church.] [Capitalism critique], 1889 (Folder FF-120, Item 1889-4)
    Pen drawing: Signed Th:Nast. 1889.
  - No title. [Mercury with the face and tail of devil stands atop building marked "The Boom Trust is sure to -" and carries a bubble pipe with bubble marked "The Soap Bubble Trust". Surrounding buildings are marked "The Bamboozle Trust", "Humbug Trust", "Burglars Trust" etc.], 1889 (Folder FF-147, Item 1889-5)
    Drawing: Signed Th:Nast. 1889. Handwritten inscription on obverse reads: "Bubbling Times; The Brass Mercury is Going up, the bigger the swindle, the greater the faith the investing public."
  - 3 drawings. Drawing a: Only a drop in the bucket, Now let him kick. Drawing b: U.S. Bonds. "The Largely Increased Purchases of Bonds for the Sinking Fund." Drawing c: Things Don't Seem to Balance! [Treasury Secretary William Windom, Wall Street bonds, taxes, pensions], 1889 (Folder FF-120, Item 1889-6 (a,b,c))
    3 pen drawings mounted together. Signed Th:Nast. 1889.
  - No title. [Figure with body like front of railroad engine is inscribed: "Standard Trusts" On base: "I Rule. That is what I am here for" Sign on wall reads: "Notice! Handle with care this august body"], 1889 (Folder FF-147, Item 1889-7)
    Pen and ink drawing: Signed Th:Nast. 1889.
  - The Darktown Fire Brigade - All Our Mettle. "Git dere fust if you's bust you trousers!", 1889 (Folder FF-120, Item 1889-8)
    Lithograph, colored: Published by Joseph Koehler. Currier & Ives Series. No. 11. Item not in folder on Feb. 1, 2022; out-slip in file dated 1/22/2019.
  - The Darktown Fire Brigade - Slightly Demoralized. "I knowed we'd make em take water!", 1889 (Folder FF-120, Item 1889-9)
    Lithograph, colored: Published by Joseph Koehler. Currier & Ives Series. No. 12. Item not in folder on Feb. 1, 2022; out-slip in file dated 1/22/2019.
  - No title. [The scene is New York Harbor with Liberty deposed from her pedestal on Bedloe's Island by grafters. One holds bag open having inscription "50 cent head money"., 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-1)
    Pen and ink drawing. Signed Th:Nast.
  - Only a Matter of Time if people vote for boss rule. [Tammany], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-2)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast. Stamped on back, "Collections of The New-York Historical Society". Acquisition(?) date on back: "Rec'd March 30, 1944".
  - No title. [In foreground, elderly man sitting on tombstone(?) speaking with Andrew Jackson; in background, a crowd with signage "Tom Jeff. Club" gathers around a statue of Thomas Jefferson], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-3)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast.
  - No title. [Scene shows railroad train at night proceeding along precipice. The figure of Death stands above striking the tracks in the train's path with his scythe. In the sky a Death head with figure of the Devil [or Chauncey Depew as jester], moneybag, and bottles of liquor are superimposed.], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-4)
  - No title. [Unidentified person dressed as a king stands alone as two courtiers approach carrying papers labelled "McKinley Bill" (Force) and "Reed Force Bill".], 1890 (Folder FF-147, Item 1890-6)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast. References to Shakespeare's Richard III written on reverse. Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct 18, 1940.
  - Above: How He Went In. Below: As Light & As Funny As "Punch". [Chauncey Depew, Harlem & New Haven railroad accident], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-7)
    Pencil drawing. Signed Th:Nast. Acquisition(?) date on back: April 27, 1942.
  - Above: How He Came Out, Below: As Black As His Tunnel. [Chauncey Depew, Harlem & New Haven railroad accident], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-8)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast. Acquisition(?) date on back: Apr. 27, 1942.
  - He not only talks people to Death, but he Dead-Heads them also., 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-9)
  - Sand in his Sugar. [Uncle Sam, Free Silver, U.S. Currency], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-10)
    Wash drawing on red paper. Unsigned. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 30 [paper torn].
  - Sam Tilden's Reform But Brings a New Swarm. [Tammany Hall], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-11)
    Pen drawing. Unsigned. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 30, 1903.
  - The Darktown Riding Class, - The Gallop. [African-Americans], 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-12)
    Lithograph, colored. Published by Currier & Ives. On back, in pencil: "Gift of Robert Goelet, March 1975".
  - Tobogganing on Darktown Hill, - An Untimely Move. "Clar de Track.", 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-13)
    Lithograph, colored. Published by Currier & Ives. *Not in File as of Feb. 3, 2022; out slip dated 1/22/2019.
  - Tobogganing on Darktown Hill, - Getting a Hist. "Dar I Knowed It.", 1890 (Folder FF-121, Item 1890-14)
  - No title. [Grover Cleveland stoops to pick up coin bearing inscription "Tariff Reform 1892". Tammany tiger affectionately rubs against him. In the background is seated figure of Uncle Sam and an unidentified figure preceded by a hastily retreating elephant. Sign reads "Direct road to Salt River. Boats to let."] (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-1)
    Pen drawing. Signed C.G.B-[ush]. Cleveland Wins (in pencil). Acquisition(?) date on front: June 21, 1905.
  - $poil$ for Revenue Only. [Tammany], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-2)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 1892.
  - The Good Shepherd. [Grover Cleveland, tariff reform], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-3)
    2 copies. Pen drawing. [by D.E. Cronin] for the Philadelphia Record after election in 1892. One copy is from The Philadelphia Record, Saturday, November 12, 1892.
  - Waiting for the Performance to Begin. [Presidential Campaign], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-4)
    Pen drawing. Sketch for Saturday, November 5, 1892. The Philadelphia Record. In pencil on back, "by D.E. Cronin".
  - Steering a Straight Course. [Presidential campaign, tariff reform], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-5)
    2 copies. Pen drawing. [by D.E. Cronin]. Sketch from cartoon in The Philadelphia Record, 1892. One copy is from The Philadelphia Record, Saturday, November 19, 1892.
  - Look Out for the Locomotive! [Grover Cleveland, New York Governor David Hill], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-6)
    Lithograph, colored. Signed Halrymple. Reproduced in Puck. Acquisition(?) date on back: July 1, 1926.
  - [In pencil] Uncle Sam "Let's see ye git It sonny." [Japan vs. U.S. for Hawaii], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-7)
    Pen drawing. Signed Canon. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 24, 1924.
  - A Question Answered. [Presidential campaign, tariff reform], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-8)
    2 copies. Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin fecit. One copy from The Philadelphia Record, Tuesday, November 8, 1892.
  - Pensions and Politics., 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-9)
    2 copies. Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin del. Sketch for cartoon in The Philadelphia Record. One copy is from The Philadelphia Record, Saturday December 3, 1892 (Title of cartoon in newspaper: Political Pensions and National Bankruptcy).
  - [In pencil] Our Tammany Snapper. No! No! Soldier ought to go back on his own words. [Drawing of Cleveland or Ulysses S. Grant with his head turned around and General Daniel Sickles headless. The remaining area is covered with inscriptions.] [Sickles's congressional campaign, Tammany], 1892 (Folder FF-122, Item 1892-10)
    Pen and ink drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 1892.
  - Cleveland's Luck. That "Wild Team." [Grover Cleveland, Presidential campaign), 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-11)
  - No title. [Caricature of Grover Cleveland in middle labeled "His Dignity and Reform Cabinet," surrounded with caricature portraits of his cabinet filled with political cronies, such as Tammany boss Richard Croker], 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-12)
  - The People Put in - $ The People's Money - The Boss Take it Out! [New York City political corruption], 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-13)
  - A Despot whose Tyranny is Felt at Every Fireside. Combine Against Capital & Labor. Old King Coal., 1892 (Folder FF-147, Item 1892-14)
  - Cleveland - The Mighty Hunter from a Japanese Legend. [Tariff reform], 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-15)
    Pencil drawing. By D.E. Cronin. Inscription reads, "Sketch for cartoon in Philadelphia Record, Nov. 13, 1892.
  - Good Missionary Work. (See Cleveland's Letter of Acceptance). [Tariff reform], 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-16)
    3 copies. Pencil drawing by D.E. Cronin. Newspaper reproduction of sketch by "D.E. Cronin fecit" from the Philadelphia Record, Tuesday, September 27, 1892 (With title: Grover Cleveland Smashing the Idols in the Joss House of High Taxation.). Also, reprinted in "Circulation Books Open to All" Tuesday, October 4, 1892.
  - Above: McKinley & Co. Counter for the Rich. Counter for the Working Man. Below: The Two Counters. "It is the shopping women who has done this ." - Ex-Speaker Reed referring to the great democratic victories of 1890. [Tariff reform, taxation], 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-17)
    2 copies. Pen drawing. By D.E. Cronin. Sketch for the Philadelphia Record. One copy from The Philadelphia Record, Saturday, October 22, 1892.
  - From The World. [Picture showing Hackett bringing satchel of campaign literature (paper money).], 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-18)
    From pen and ink drawing signed McD. Below date: October 7th, 1892.
  - The Darktown Bicycle Club - On Parade. "Hooray for de Rumatic! Don't she glide lubly.", 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-19)
    Lithograph, colored. Drawn by J. Cameron, published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition: Gift of Robert Goelet, May 1976.
  - The Darktown Bicycle Club - Knocked Out. "Dar! I knowed dem odd fellers was a breedin mischief.", 1892 (Folder FF-123, Item 1892-20)
  - An Object Lesson in Silver. [Devaluation of silver dollar], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893- No #)
    No pen drawing by D.E. Cronin in folder. Reproduction from The Philadelphia Record, Tuesday, July 25, 1893.
  - Above: More Drops in the Bucket! Below: "One Demnition Horrid Grind." [Tammany], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-1)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 1893.
  - No title. [Federal officer ousts man carrying bag labelled "Dishonesty Worse than Dynamite" from offices of National Bank. Waste paper basket has contents labelled "The Responsibility of Directors" and "Duty". Officer carries ax and fasces labelled "Congress" in hip pocket.], 1893 (Folder FF-147, Item 1893-2)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 1893. Acquisition: Purchase, Nov. 15, 1938, Wilbur Fund.
  - Thankgiving: The Scare-Crow Dismantled. [The Sherman Act], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-3)
    Pen drawing. By [D.E. Cronin]. Cartoon for Phila. Record Nov. 1893.
  - Signs of Reviving Confidence: The Old Stocking, Stove-pipe, and Coffee Pot Hoarders go back to the banks. [Gold standard], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-4)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin fecit. Sketch for cartoon for [Philadelphia] Record 1893.
  - Recent Immigration. Uncle Sam: "Say, do you see those figures? Well, I think it's pretty near time to haul up the bridge! Self-preservation is the first law of nature.", 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-5)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin del. Sketch for Philadelphia Record cartoon 1893.
  - Assessing the Income Tax. Proposed new army of Official Inquisitors., 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-6)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin fecit. Cartoon for Phila. record 1893. "The First Rubbernecks"
  - At the National Banquet Table. Chorus of Honest Veterans: "The bald-headed pensioner must go!", 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-7)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin del 1893. Sketch for cartoon Phila. Record.
  - A Statesman of the Period: "He can see the barn-door but he can't see the barn." [Political corruption, special interests], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-8)
    Pen drawing. Signed Cronin. Cartoon for Phila. Record 1893.
  - The National Workshop. Uncle Sam: "There boys! I've put up that sign and if you don't stop this dangerous business, I Swow! I shall turn off the steam and close up the concern." [Dollar/currency devaluation], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-9)
    Pen drawing. By [D.E. Cronin]. Sketch for cartoon for [Phila.] Record 1893.
  - The American Police Adopt the Russian Helmet: By Order of a Secret Session of the U.S. Senate. [Deportation], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-10)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin fecit.
  - What the Southern Senators will find if they tear down the Democratic Platform. [Sherman Silver Purchase Act], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-11)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin fecit. A sketch for cartoon for Phila. Record 1893.
  - Too Big for the Boat. [Growth of civil service offices], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-12)
    Pen drawing. Signed Cro[nin]. Cartoon for Phila. record 1893.
  - Democratic Engineers to the Rescue. [Tariff reform], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-13)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin fecit. Sketch for cartoon in Phila. Record 1893.
  - Preparing for Thanksgiving. Uncle Sam: "I guess I will keep that tough gobbler over until next year. Something plainer will serve for my dinner this year, without any political sauce." [Republicans, elections], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-14)
    Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin del. Sketch for cartoon for [Phila.] Record 1893.
  - Uncle Sam's Cabinet of Curiosities: "The various administrations have presented me with a good many curiosities but this from Secretary Gresham of an American Shield supporting a Royal Crown ..." [Hawaii], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-15)
    Pen drawing. Signed Cronin. Sketch for cartoon for Phila. Record 1893.
  - Campaign of Education - Continued. The Ptolemaic and Copernican Theories Contrasted., 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-16)
    2 copies. Pen drawing. Signed D.E. Cronin del. Sketch for cartoon in Phila. Record 1893. Also, a reproduction of the cartoon from The Philadelphia Record, Saturday, December 17, 1892, that diffders somewhat and with a diffderent title: The Financial Universe. The Old Theory and the New."
  - "In God We Trust." (Our Only Hope) But not in "Silver Dick." [Richard Bland], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-17)
  - No title. [Uncle Sam is embracing Gladstone who holds paper inscribed: "Irish Home Rule." John Bull watches disapprovingly. Sign on wall reads: To All Irish Rulers Abroad! Come Home to Rule.], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-18)
    Pen and ink drawing. Signed Th:Nast. On back (in pencil) "Our Grateful Endorsement. U.S. By giving the Irish their own country to rule, you [unreadable] the World in general and the United States in particular."
  - The Splendid Crop Prospects. [Exports, Sherman Silver Purchase Act], 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-No #)
    Reproduction of pen drawing in The Philadelphia Record, Saturday June 24, 1893.
  - The Control of the United States Senate., 1893 (Folder FF-124, Item 1893-No #)
    Reproduction of pen drawing (signed Cronin) in The Philadelphia Record, Thursday, October 19, 1893.
  - Below: Richard is not Quite Himself. Above: Get the People's Mind on "The Necessity for a Prompt Settlement of the Tariff Question - resolution adopted by Tammany Hall (up to date) [Tammany Hall; Richard Croker], 1894 (Folder FF-125, Item 1894-1)
    Pen and ink drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 94.
  - Below: "The Age of Ghoulishness. $treet Barricade against Honest Business." Above: "Get thee behind ME Satan!!!" Flanking picture: "Is life worth living?" and other text, 1894 (Folder FF-147, Item 1894-2)
    Pen and ink drawing: Signed Th:Nast.
  - The Darktown Fire Brigade - Investigating a Smoke. Parson - No Sah De Meetin House Aint afire, but de Congregation am taking a Smoke of de World's best terbakker., 1894 (Folder FF-125, Item 1894-3)
    Lithograph, colored: Published by Joseph Koehler. Currier & Ives Series. No. 13. Acquisition(?) date on back: May 20, 1927.
  - The Darktown Fire Brigade - Taking a Rest. Foreman - Right you is Parson dis terbakker beats de deck., 1894 (Folder FF-125, Item 1894-4)
    Lithograph, colored: Published by Joseph Koehler. Currier & Ives Series. No. 14. Acquisition(?) date on back: May 20, 1927.
  - No title. [Unidentified man is assisted upstairs by Father Time. The Devil "Henry" peers from out of the top of a barrel of soft soap.] [Money, currency], 1895 (Folder FF-148, Item 1895-1)
    Pen drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 1895.
  - Below: The First British Bomb in Wall Street. [Written on smoke caused by explosion:] American Investments., 1895 (Folder FF-148, Item 1895-2)
    Pen and ink drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 1895.
  - American Union vs. Western Union ... A Very Appropriate Stained Glass Window/In memory of the Prince of Appropriators. [Jay Gould], 1895 (Folder FF-148, Item 1895-3)
    Signed Th:Nast. 1895.
  - [In blue pencil] "Floated at Last." (To Be Used In Case McKinley Is Elected) Tues. Night., 1896 (Folder FF-126, Item 1896-2)
    Pen drawing. Signed A.Z. Baker. Acquisition(?) date on back: May 1, 1918.
  - Farmer McKinley Takes Off His Coat., 1896 (Folder FF-126, Item 1896-3)
    Photograph of pen drawing by W.A. Rogers reproduced in Harper's Weekly, July 25, 1896. *Not in file as of Feb. 10, 2022
  - The Silver-Tongued Ventriloquist and His Dummies. If the Show Succeeds, He'll Get All the Profits., 1896 (Folder FF-126, Item 1896-4)
    Photograph of a lithograph by F. Opper reproduced on cover of Puck, Aug. 12, 1896. *Not in file as of Feb. 10, 2022
  - Triumph of Nero-Reszke., 1896 (Folder FF-126, Item 1896-no #)
    Reproduced Drawing. Signed T. Fleming. Reproduced in Supplement to The New York Musical Courier, December 30, 1896. Acquisition noted on back: 2002, Schreyer donation.
  - No title. [Image of Native American man surrounded by rampaging goats and rams; reindeer pulling St. Nicholas's sleigh in sky], 1896 (Folder FF-148, Item 1896-No #)
    Pem and ink drawing. Signed, but name unclear. (D. Benrd? Beard?)
  - A Vote for Low is a Vote for Platt, Puritanism and Hard Times. [Seth Low, New York mayoral election], 1897 (Folder FF-148, Item 1897-5)
    Reproduction on poster of pen and ink drawing signed "Dalrymple". American union label: LIP & BA. Acquisition(?) date on front: March 21, 1933
  - Putting the ball in play. $70,000,000 appropriations inside this greater New York football., 1897 (Folder FF-127, Item 1897-No #)
    Caricature after the design by D. McCarthy in The Sunday World, Oct. 17, 1897. *Not in file as of Feb. 10, 2022.
  - The Manila Incident Reflected in the Faces of Europe [Spanish-American War], 1898 (Folder FF-127, Item 1898-1)
    Pen lithograph, colored. Signed Cory '98. [Reproduced in Puck]. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 18, 1942.
  - Below: Our Standing Toast. Above: Our Army & Navy., 1898 (Folder FF-148, Item 1898-2)
    Pen and ink drawing. Signed Th:Nast. 1898.
  - The Flag that Dewey Hoists on Manila Shall Never Come Down. [McKinley, Philippines], 1898 (Folder FF-127, Item 1898-No #)
    Drawing by Victor Gillam. Published by Arkell Publishing Co. Sackett & Wilhelms Litho & Prg Co. From "Judge." Hawaii, Cuba, and Puerto Rico also depicted as children clinging to the U.S.
  - The New Uncle Sam. John B. [John Bull] (in background): "My Hi, Sammy, Your Popper 'Ardly Knows You!" [U.S. empire in comparison to Britain], 1898 (Folder FF-127, Item 1898-4)
    Drawing signed by Cory - 98. Reproduced in The Bee.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 1 of 13). From "The Bee"., 1898 (Folder FF-128, Item 1898-No #)
    16 sheets. Includes drawings principally by John Campbell Cory. Depictions of specific individuals include, among others, Joseph Pulitzer, James Gordon Bennett, maximo Gomez, William J. Bryan, and William R. Hearst.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 2 of 13). From "The Bee", "Up To Date", + Miscellaneous Publications., 1898 (Folder FF-129, Item 1898-No #)
    20 sheets. Includes drawings by John Campbell Cory, H.A. Thiede, and others. Specific individuals depicted include, among others, General Nelson A. Miles, Edwin L. Godkin, Commodore Schley, and various diplomats.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 3 of 13). From "The Judge" (Double page spreads)., 1898 (Folder FF-130, Item 1898-No #)
    22 sheets. Sackett & Wilhelms Litho & Prg. Co. Drawings by Eugene Zimmerman, Victor Gillam, and Grant E. Hamilton.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 4 of 13). From "The Judge". (Double page spreads)., 1898 (Folder FF-131, Item 1898-No #)
    25 sheets. Sackett & wilhelms Litho & Prg. Co, Drawings by Victor Gillam, Grant E. Hamilton, Eugene Zimmerman, and some by both Hamilton and Zimmerman.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 5 of 13). From "The Judge"., 1898 (Folder FF-132, Item 1898-No #)
    20 sheets. Sackett & Wilhelms Litho & Prg. Co. Drawings by Grant E. Hamilton, Victor Gillam, and Eugene Zimmerman. Unrelated directly to the war images, this folder also includes the April 30, 1898, cover art for the "Bicycle Number" featuring red, white and blue-clad women on bicycles.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 6 of 13). From "The Judge"., 1898 (Folder FF-133, Item 1898-No #)
    20 sheets. Sackett & Wilhelms Litho & Ptg. Co. Drawings principally by Grant E. Hamilton, Arthur Young(?), Victor Gillam, and Eugene Zimmerman.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 7 of 13). From "The Judge"., 1898 (Folder FF-134, Item 1898-No #)
    20 sheets. Sackett & Wilhelms Litho & Prg Co. Drawings principally by Eugene Zimmerman, Grant E. Hamilton, Schultze, Victor Gillam, and Otho Cushing.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 8 of 13). From "The Judge"., 1898 (Folder FF-135, Item 1898-No #)
    10 sheets. Sackett & Wilhemls Llitho & Prg Co. Drawings principally by Victor Gillam, Grant E. Hamilton, and Eugene Zimmerman.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 9 of 13). From "Puck" (Double sheets), 1898 (Folder FF-136, Item 1898-No #)
    20 sheets. J. Ottmann Lith Co. Drawings principally by Louis Dalrymple, Joseph Keppler, J.S. Pughe, and Samuel Ehrhart.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 10 of 13). From "Puck" (Double sheets)., 1898 (Folder FF-137, Item 1898-No #)
    26 sheets. J. Ottmann Lith Co. Drawings principally by Louis Dalrymple, Joseph Keppler, J.S. Pughe, and Samuel Ehrhart.
  - Spanish-American War. (Folder 11 of 13). From "Puck"., 1898, 1906 (Folder FF-138, Item 1898-No #)